# Will Dudley - Environment & Tech Artist

I am a skilled 3D artist with 5 years experience and have worked on four great mobile games and two AAA published titles. I enjoy working closely with the whole development team to create fantastic looking games that we can be proud of. I have a keen creative mind and am always brimming with ideas and concepts that I can't wait to try out.

I enjoy tackling problems from all angles, so as well as my skills in 3D art, I am developing skills in tool scripting and shader creation. I am always looking to improve myself, and enjoy collaborating with others to find techniques and practices that will enhance the quality and speed of the work we produce.

#### Skills:

Hard Surface Modelling	Style Development	Rapid Prototyping

Shader Creation Art Tools Development Pipeline Development

Texturing Lighting Asset Integration

# **Experience:**

Freelance Artist - August 2016 - Present

For the past few months I have been doing freelance work. This has included Environment Art, Character Art, and Rapid prototyping.

**Marmalade Game Studios** - Lead Environment Artist - January 2015 - August 2016 Artist - April 2013 - January 2015

# Projects:

Rize: Zombies, Transformers: Robots In Disguise, Hasbro Arcade, Littlest Pet Shop: Your World



## Responsibilities:

Project Lead Artist
Vehicle Art
Visual Effects
Rapid Prototyping
Level Assembly Planning
Managing Outsource

Environment Design and Art Character Art Style Development Pre-production Art Animation Asset Integration **Lionhead** - Facial Animator March - June 2012 Project:



# Responsibilities:

Facial animation at Lionhead was created with a morph-target based system. This was primarily used to create animations using video reverence from mo-cap shoots, but also animating to a audio track without video reference.

Rare Ltd - 3D Artist

March - December 2011

Project:





Over the development of Kinect Sports Season Two I took on many roles. Primarily creating in-game assets such as sports equipment, I also spent time rigging props for animation, and tracking down and solving bugs found by the QA team. I was kept on for the development of the DLC, and am very proud that some of the new game modes rely entirely on new art that I created.

Responsibilities:

Modelling

**Asset Creation** 

Character and Prop LODs

Asset Integration using In-House

Software

Mechanical Animation and Rigging

Texturing Shaders

**Bug Fixing** 

**Xbox Dashboard Themes** 

#### **Game Jams:**

I love Game Jams and and very proud to have won the King Game Jam and the Great British Winter Game Jam, and come second in the Creative Assembly Game Jam at EGX Rezzed.







# **Software Experience:**

Maya 3DS Max Unity 3D Coat Zbrush Source Engine

Adobe Photoshop
Unreal Development Kit

#### Interests:

Other than video games, I enjoy reading and cinema. I'm always looking for an exciting new book or film, or to catch up on a classic that I may have missed. I also enjoy travel and have spent some time touring Costa Rica with World Challenge in 2007, and spent 10 weeks touring South East Asia in 2009.

#### **Qualifications:**

2007-2010 University of

**Portsmouth** 

BSc (Hons) Computer

Animation 2:1

2005-2007 Godalming College

A - Levels:

Design and Technology

English Literature

Psychology General Studies

2000-2005 Glebelands School

GCSEs:

Mathematics

English

**English Literature** 

Physics Chemistry Biology Drama

**D&T** Resistant

Materials

French History

## Referees:

Terry Lee - Producer, Marmalade Game Studio - terryjleee@gmail.com

Aaron Ludlow - Producer, Marmalade Game Studio - aaron.ludlow@playstack.com

Mike Rosser - Creative Director - mike.rosser@gmail.com

Andrew Lindsay - Director of Animation, Lionhead - alindsay@microsoft.com

Andy Betts - Art Principal, Rare Ltd - abetts@rare.co.uk

Steve Mayles - Character Lead, Rare Ltd - smayles@rare.co.uk

Paul Cunningham - Assistant Art Manager, Rare Ltd - pcunning@rare.co.uk

Andy Bain - Lecturer, University of Portsmouth - andy.bain@port.ac.uk

Paul Charisse - Lecturer, University of Portsmouth - paul.charisse@port.ac.uk

Jules Pettitt - Lecturer, University of Portsmouth - jules.pettitt@port.ac.uk